export const chapter = "Chapter - 2: The Earliest Societies";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "During which age did stone remain the chief material used?",
        optionA: "Chalcolithic or Copper Age",
        optionB: "Bronze Age",
        optionC: "Stone Age",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following materials was NOT used during the Stone Age besides stone?",
        optionA: "Bone",
        optionB: "Wood",
        optionC: "Gold",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the chronological range of the Palaeolithic Age?",
        optionA: "From circa 5,000 BC to about 4,000 BC",
        optionB: "From circa 5,00,000 BC to circa 10,000 BC",
        optionC: "From circa 10,000 BC to 8,000 BC",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Stone Age can be divided into three periods based on the development of tools. What are these three periods?",
        optionA: "Early Stone Age, Middle Stone Age, Modern Age",
        optionB: "Palaeolithic Age, Mesolithic Age, Neolithic Age",
        optionC: "Stone Age I, Stone Age II, Stone Age III",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What method did Early Man use to shape his tools during the Palaeolithic Age?",
        optionA: "Fire",
        optionB: "Pressure-flaking",
        optionC: "Electricity",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What materials were used to make stone tools during the Stone Age?",
        optionA: "Gold and silver",
        optionB: "Basalt, flint, sandstone, shells, and antlers",
        optionC: "Copper and bronze",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During which period did Early Man start to domesticate wild animals and practice primitive agriculture?",
        optionA: "Palaeolithic Age",
        optionB: "Mesolithic Age",
        optionC: "Neolithic Age",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question: "How did Early Man learn to light a fire?",
        optionA: "He used matches",
        optionB: "He struck stone on stone to produce sparks",
        optionC: "He used magnifying glasses",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is believed to be Early Man's reaction to natural phenomena like storms and lightning?",
        optionA: "He enjoyed them",
        optionB: "He prayed to them",
        optionC: "He ignored them",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which region in India is known for its cave art from the Palaeolithic Age?",
        optionA: "Bhimbetka Caves",
        optionB: "Ellora Caves",
        optionC: "Ajanta Caves",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "During the Stone Age, stone remained the chief material used. This period can be divided into three ages: Palaeolithic Age, Mesolithic Age, and __________ Age.",
        optionA: "Neolithic",
        optionB: "Bronze",
        optionC: "Copper",
        correctAnswer: "Neolithic",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early Man was a __________ during the Palaeolithic Age, hunting animals for food and skin, gathering food, and wandering from place to place.",
        optionA: "Farmer",
        optionB: "Hunter-Gatherer-Wanderer",
        optionC: "Blacksmith",
        correctAnswer: "Hunter-Gatherer-Wanderer",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early Man learned to shape his tools using two methods: stone-on-stone method and __________ method.",
        optionA: "Pressure-flaking",
        optionB: "Welding",
        optionC: "Casting",
        correctAnswer: "Pressure-flaking",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Stone tools made from materials such as basalt, flint, sandstone, shells, and antlers were used for various purposes, including digging the ground to access edible roots and crafting stitching needles, arrows, and spears. These tools were essential for __________.",
        optionA: "Building shelters",
        optionB: "Lighting fires",
        optionC: "Survival",
        correctAnswer: "Survival",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early Man domesticated wild animals for meat, milk, and skin during the __________ Age, while also learning to grow his food.",
        optionA: "Palaeolithic",
        optionB: "Mesolithic",
        optionC: "Neolithic",
        correctAnswer: "Neolithic",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Some tools from the Mesolithic Age were tied or hefted in wood, demonstrating Early Man's __________.",
        optionA: "Innovation",
        optionB: "Nomadic lifestyle",
        optionC: "Isolation",
        correctAnswer: "Innovation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early people lived in different places, and their development did not take place uniformly. Some groups took longer to learn things like lighting a fire or domesticating animals. Different groups were developing at different __________.",
        optionA: "Ages",
        optionB: "Rates",
        optionC: "Locations",
        correctAnswer: "Rates",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Prehistoric sites in the Deccan, like Attirampakkam and Chirki-Nevasa, have yielded artifacts from the Palaeolithic Age to the Neolithic Age, shedding light on the __________ of the prehistoric people living in those areas.",
        optionA: "Culture",
        optionB: "Skill and intelligence",
        optionC: "Language",
        correctAnswer: "Skill and intelligence",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the Deccan, the stone mostly used during the Palaeolithic Age was __________, which could be easily broken into any shape.",
        optionA: "Flint",
        optionB: "Copper",
        optionC: "Marble",
        correctAnswer: "Flint",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Palaeolithic tools were crude and less efficient during the Early Stone Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Early Man primarily relied on farming during the Stone Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mesolithic Age marked the beginning of domesticating wild animals.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The use of stone-on-stone and pressure-flaking methods were important in shaping stone tools during the Stone Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early Man's interaction with other groups led to the formation of various social groups.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early Man learned to make fire by striking steel against stone.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During the Palaeolithic Age, Early Man wore animal skins for protection from cold and wind.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early Man used iron oxides, charcoal, and ochre to create colorful cave paintings during the Stone Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Stone Age can be divided into four distinct ages based on the primary material used.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The development of stone tools during the Stone Age was marked by the gradual improvement in their efficiency and size.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
